# Qichun (Jackson) Yu

Accounting & Finance · Data Scientist · Full-Stack Developer

	204-899-2862
$\bowtie$	qyu2@academic.rrc.ca
	jacksonyu92.github.io
	github.com/JacksonYu92

### Summary

Entry-level data analytics professional; recently completed the Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate. Proficient knowledge in statistics, mathematics, and analytics. Specialized in business requirement analysis, data extraction and data visualization; ETL (extract, transform, loading), data integration and validation. Excellent understanding of business operations and analytics tools for effective analyses of data.

#### Education

## **Data Science and Machine Learning**

September 2021 - Now

Red River College Polytech

Winnipeg, MB

- Relevant Coursework: Data Science and Machine Learning, Programming Logic, Linear Algebra, Statistics and Probability, Transforming Data Into Databases, Python Essentials With Data Analysis, Data Management, Supervised Machine Learning, Unsupervised Machine Learning, Introduction to Artificial Intelligence, Neural Networks and Deep Learning
- Expected completion: April 2023

## Bachelor of Commerce (Hons), Major in Accounting and Finance

May 2011 - August 2015

University of Manitoba, Asper School of Business

Winnipeg, MB

 Knowledgeable in Financial Accounting, Managerial Accounting, Intermediate Accounting - Assets, Intermediate Accounting – Equities, Cost Accounting, Accounting Theory, Corporate Finance, Investments, Financial Markets and Institutions, Corporate Finance Theory and Practice, Financial Management Practices

#### Certificate

## **Google Data Analytics Professional Certificate**Google

May 2022 – July 2022

Online

- Completed extensive six-month job-ready Google Career Certificate training within three months
- Demonstrated hands-on experience with data cleaning, data visualization, project management, interpreting, and communicating data analytics findings. Confidence in transforming complex data into actionable and clear insights (Tableau). Fluency in computer programming languages (R) and a solid understanding of databases (SQL).

#### Skills

- **Programming Languages**: Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, React, Node, Flask, APIs, Git
- Data Science & Machine Learning: Python (Pandas, Matplotlib, Numpy, Seaborn, Scikit-learn, Jupyter Notebook), R, MongoDB, Spark, PowerBI, Tableau, SQL, MS Excel (VLOOKUP, pivotable, match, advanced formula)

## **Work Experience**

#### **Production Manager**

May 2016 - August 2021

TheraVape Inc.
Winnipeg, MB

- Project management and problem resolution, ensuring compliance with Quality Management Systems (ISO9001)
- Review processing schedules or production orders to make decisions concerning inventory requirements, staffing requirements, work procedures, or duty assignments, considering budgetary limitations and time constraints
- Ensured products met or exceeded client expectations
- Ensured that materials, labor, or equipment are used efficiently to meet production targets
- Maintained accurate and up-to-date batching database and filing system (Excel)

# Qichun (Jackson) Yu

## Accounting & Finance · Data Scientist · Full-Stack Developer

☐ 204-899-2862

☐ qyu2@academic.rrc.ca

☐ jacksonyu92.github.io

☐ github.com/JacksonYu92

- Redesign operational processes, improved training and staff utilization, reduced number of staff by half while sales go up by 50%
- Reduced manufacturing costs by 50%, maximized profits to the company by reducing waste and cutting unnecessary costs (QuickBooks, Excel, Financial Report)

#### **Project Experience**

## E-commerce Developer

September 2021 – Now Winnipeg, MB

Tattogo, tattogo.com

- Develop, design, prototype, build, debug and maintain eCommerce solutions
- Designing textual and graphical content including logo and product illustrations for the website
- Frequently worked with Adobe PS and Canva to design custom elements, social media posts, and product videos
- Developing Brand Awareness, increasing website exposure
- Developing online marketing and promotional strategies, optimizing Google and Facebook Ads Campaign, managing social media accounts
- Set up email marketing flows, integrate Klavlyo automation solutions with Shopify

#### **Project Manager & Founder**

May 2018 - May 2019

Aim Smart Corp. (start-up)

Winnipeg, MB

- Develop and interpret organizational goals, policies, and procedures
- Manage and direct all international trade, maintain a good relationship with suppliers
- Review project plans to plan and coordinate project activity
- Direct or coordinate an organization's financial or budget activities to fund operations, maximize investments
- Identify, develop, or evaluate marketing strategy

#### **Business Manager & Co-founder**

October 2013 - December 2014

Miniwin Electronic Commerce (start-up)

Winnipeg, MB

- Managed and updated the company's website content using WordPress.
- Prepared and delivered business plans including forecasting, budgets, cost and SWOT analysis.
- Planned and direct activities such as marketing, assisted in designing advertisements to promote business awareness.
- Attracted potential business partners through networking and meetings to increase our client base.

#### **Awards**

## **Received award in Fermat Mathematics Contest**

2009

University of Waterloo